UI / UX Product Designer

https://support999.github.io/amitsaxena-portfolio/



Hard-working professional with 12 years of experience and 7 years a proven knowledge of application development. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the UI/UX Product Designer role at your company.



Skills

- **UX**: Sketched, Persona, Wireframe, Prototyping, User Flows, Flow-Charts, UCD, TDD Documentations, Functional Documentation.
- Designing Tools: Adobe XD, Figma, Invision, Apps Design, justIn Mind, Website Template Design.



Engagement experience

I have worked as UI / UX Product Designer for clients. I was involved in interacting with the functional owners to understand the requirement and subsequently designing an efficient and optimum solution for the same. I was also involved in creating viable specification and acceptance criteria for the identified solutions and Ideation . UX Design testing strategy plan and participating in or managing user acceptance testing.

In other engagements in my career, I was involved in coordinating with Business for the business/functional requirements, Design & Development, developing reports. I have been a part of the team in critical situations and supported, helped and shared the work. Have mingled with the team members of all cadres. I have indulged in corrective communication and achieved desired results in the deliverables of important objects.



Professional Experience

Present Aug-2020

UX Product Designer

OpinVerse Pvt. Ltd.

In house project for Digital Marketing .OpinVerse https://opinverse.com/

- Understanding of whole project and create the Flow chart / wireframe as well.
- UCD architecture with the use of JustIn-Mind tool .
- Create Documentation for the development ..
- Manage Team for back-end development with API and Mobile application Development.
- Create UX / UI Design for Mobile app Adobe XD, Figma
- Testing, review and Architecture with Project Team.

UI / UX Product Designer

https://support999.github.io/amitsaxena-portfolio/

Dec 2018 - July - 2020

UX Designer

Crayonsys Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

In house project similar Like combination of Outlook and what's app . "Pipassport"

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pipassport.passportsuite https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pipassport.ping

- Discussion of whole project ideation and create the Flow Design , wireframe and Persona with Sketch flows
- User-Centered Design (UCD) created to target the end user experience about the product with the use of "Pidoco".
- Create Documentation for the development.
- Create UX / UI Design for Mobile app Adobe XD, Figma , illustrator, Photoshop .

Feb 2017 - Nov 2018

UI / UX Designer

SAA Consultancy, UK

- 1) This project is for the UK Hospital Management Application . "TrueNorth-App"
- As this project is for UK Hospital ,This was totally a great and new experience to create the wireframe Prototyping .
- User-Centered Design (UCD) created to target the end user experience about the product with the use of JustIn-Mind.
- Create Documentation for the development ...
- Create UX / UI Design for Mobile app Adobe XD, Figma
 - 2) Hospital management project for UK . "BedManagement", "BedRequest"
- Understanding of whole project and create the wireframe as well.
- User-Centered Design (UCD) created to target the end user experience about the product with the use of JustIn-Mind.
- Create Documentation for the development ...
- Create UX / UI Design for Mobile app Adobe XD, Figma, illustrator, Persona.

March 2015 - Jan 2017

UI / UX Designer

Nine One Solution

- 1) Project is for Car Marketing Company for Canada , Advertising , web and Application designing .
- As client having only basic idea project and create the wireframe and flow chart as well.

UI / UX Product Designer

https://support999.github.io/amitsaxena-portfolio/

- Create Documentation for the development ...
- Create UX / UI Design for Mobile app Axure , Photoshop .
- Testing , review and Architecture with Project Team .
- 2) The projects is for clients for Mercedes and Toyota the global Car manufacturing company. To support and offer high quality, innovative solutions as per their Requirements.
- Create Documentation for the development.
- Create UX / UI Design for Mobile app Axure prototyping, Photoshop.
- Website / Admin / CRM / Franchise Module design

Jan 2014 - Feb 2015

UI / UX Designer

Ebunch (Canada)

- 1. The project was for Food services, It gave me an opportunity to work as a UI/UX Designer.
- Create Documentation for the development .
- Create UX / UI Design for Mobile app , illustrator, Photoshop, Axure .
- Website / Admin / CRM / Module design .

Nov 2011 - Dec - 2014

Business Analyst

Kangaroo Software

The projects is for an Australian Client, a global IT company and software Service provider that believes in the power of Information Technologies. To support and offer high quality, innovative solutions from everyday essentials to instrument for web, Mobile application.

- Requirement gathering from the users and preparing technical specification, Develop wire-frame, Web(PHP, Wordpress) and Mobile Applications .
- Involved in the business requirements development phase, understanding the Clients requirements and providing the solutions to user requirements.
- Delivering and working along with the offshore development team of 20 members.

September 2008 - October 2011

Business Analyst

Korea Link Share

The projects is for a global Garments company and software Service provider that believes in the power of Information Technologies. To support and offer high quality, innovative solutions from everyday essentials to instrument for every web, every application. All from the most cited different brands. Which is based out of North America, South Korea. I have been involved in development for its Global requirements.

UI / UX Product Designer

https://support999.github.io/amitsaxena-portfolio/

- Delivering and working along with the off-shore development team.
- Management and Development Activity for the package solutions project.
- Create the Technical documentation and wire frame.
- Worked on different types of web and Mobile development.



Education

University – Course / Education
JIVAJI UNIVERCITY Gwalior – B.Sc Computer Science (2006)



Contacts



+91-9617332777



asaxena2@outlook.com success19191@gmail.com

Recognition: Successfully Completed End to end Implementation and Upgrade projects, appreciated for my work by customer as well as the team & Company. Created and presented an excellent image of the company and its services to customers, and coordinated and communicated well with clientele and management at all levels. Appreciations received from every customer he worked so for.